

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211







Technical Architect seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, Application Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Core Java, J2EE, HTML 5, CSS

3, JavaScript, jQuery, Oracle, MySQL, DynamoDB, AJAX, XML, XSL, Akamai, Hibernate

Current Designation: Technical Architect -Core Java/J2EE Total Experience: 17 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Sopra Steria Notice Period: 3 Months

Current Location: Delhi Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Biomedical]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming

Role: Tech Architect

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Technical Architect, Software Development, Application Programming, Application Maintenance, Project

Management, Requirement Analysis, Core Java, J2EE, HTML 5, CSS

3,JavaScript,jQuery,Oracle,MySQL,DynamoDB,AJAX,XML,XSL,Akamai,Hibernate,Eclipse RCP

Verified : Le Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 18-Jan-21 Last Modified: 18-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Summary

Result-oriented Professional with 17 years of experience in Software Development, Application Programming, Application Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Core Java, J2EE, HTML 5, CSS 3, JavaScript, jQuery, Oracle, MySQL, DynamoDB, AJAX, XML, XSL, Akamai, Hibemate.

Work Experience

Sopra Steria as Technical Architect -Core Java/J2EE Sep 2006 to Till Date

Project Name: UPOV PlutoDB March 2020 - till Date

UPOV: Pluto DB required an interface to collect and process Plant Breeder's data and store it in the UPOV database for publishing and searching .The project is designed to empower each breeder to process the plant rights faster and grow profitable and sustainable varieties of Plants Kev features

Understanding every constraint and problems faced by users. Use of highly efficient, available, scalable and cost effective systems.

- AWS, Java, Elastic Search, Serverless Framework, Easy deployment with Scripts, Open AM, OIDC, Angular 8 Accept and upload of different user formats of data
- All Countries can upload content at the same time.
- Automatic processing, No manual intervention.
- Application is interactive and gives fast solutions to UPOV and users
- Customizable services and functions
- Fast search with added features

Project Name: UPOV-PRISMA November 2019 - February 2020

UPOV Prisma an online service for PVP application for collection of data from the patent applications.

Kev features

It required the UI to be reformed and integrated to a JAVA UI framework called ZK framework. Various integrations of pages and their functionality integrations were required. In involved Java, ZK framework, HTML CSS and java script.

Project Name: WIPO May 2015 - March 2019

WIPO stands for World Intellectual Property Organization multilingual terminology portal gives access to scientific and technical terms derived from patent documents. It helps promote accurate and consistent use of terms across different languages, and makes it easier to search and share scientific and technical knowledge. Key features

Developed by WIPO language experts and terminologists.

It's based on the Apache Search engine, Lucene which does the search on the patents and wrapped by Angular 4, HTML 5 and CSS 3, JavaScript and jQuery with Java, JSF, JPA, DAO technology stack to render the UI to the users. It uses 10 languages for translation - Arabic, Chinese, English, French, German, Japanese, Korean, Portuguese, Russian and Spanish.



Important

· Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

All the content has been validated and given a term reliability score.

If there is no equivalent in the target language in the database, WIPO's machine translation engine may offer a translation proposal.

Integrated with PATENTSCOPE so one can search the entire PATENTSCOPE corpus for terms and their equivalents in other languages.

Responsibility:

Develop, test and enhance the existing website. Worked on the UI components for enhancement of the features based on HTM_/CSS and JavaScript/jQuery. Worked on integration of the new database for indexes enabling the search on a new term set

Worked on the implementation of Responsive Web Design project to enable the website to be viewed on Mobile Devices.

Worked on reforming the UI from JSF to Angular 4.

Project Name: Knowledge Management June 2013 - April 2015

The Knowledge Management program is one point access to all employees for all categories of organization data in various geographies (India/UK, France and Germany). The main objective of these data migrations was to decommission old repositories in various geographical locations and unifying and consolidating on SP. A Community SharePoint site including blogging, discussions, events and a document library. Responsibility:

My responsibility as Migration Consultant was to migrate data from legacy systems to Sharepoint using DocAve tool. Created an interface using Eclipse RCP tool for the data to be displayed for the users.

Project Name: The CLUB October 2007 - April 2012

The Club, project involves the content management website for the leading and most used websites in UK. The Department of Health (www.dh.gov.uk) and Direct Gov (www.direct.gov.uk) are its primary members. CQC (Care Quality Commission) has recently joined the clientele. The contents, reports documents etc. are uploaded by the gov.

HCL Technologies Ltd as Software Specialist

Nov 2003 to Sep 2006

Project Summary

GMdb.com is a content Management System providing platform to manage Research, Sales and Trading publications. EDS (Electronic Distribution System) manages the research distribution published by analyst whereas through CMS (Client Management System) permissions of web sites and research distributions are controlled. The contents can be uploaded using different mechanisms like upload applet, Flash Upload, email, fip upload etc. Publications are distributed to different systems like Web, Email, Bloomberg, DBChat, Multexetc.

The Global Markets website aggregates product-related content (research, trade ideas, market commentary, Equities, rate information), quantitative tools and links to trading capability in one place for easy sales and client

access.GMdb.com is a global system with a Centralized content management database and distribution system for all Global Market products. Includes advanced data upload and download.

Clients can be individually granted permissions to access specific sections or pages. Consequently, content, tools and analytics that are for internal use only

Archive and Search Functionality. Asearch engine permits users to search by keyword, analyst, geographic location, currencies, industry classification, product type and content type across an archive database.

On-line Subscription Management: An on-line subscription management system permits clients to manage their research subscriptions in an intuitive manner.

Internet site: https://gm-secure.db.com/ Intranet site: https://gm.db.com/ Development Platform: J2EE Platform (Servlets, JSP, XML) JDK 1.4 Application Server: Apache, Tomcat, Weblogic, JBoss 4.

Database : Oracle 9i.

User Interface : HTML/ CSS/ JSP

Role/Contribution : 1.Interaction with the client for requirements gathering.

- 2. Problem Analysis and Design.
- 3. Freezing the specs and development till integration.

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E (Biomedical) from BMS College Of Engineering, Bangalore in 2002

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used	Experience
CORE JAVA, J2EE		
HTML 5, CSS 3		
JavaScript, JQuery		
Linux, Windows		
Oracle, MySQL, DynamoDB		
AJAX, XML, XSL, Akamai		
Apache Lucene, Oracle UCM		
Hibernate, Eclipse RCP, Elastic Stack		
JBoss, IBMWebsphere		
Apache, Wildfly		
Elastic search engine		
AWS, Serverless		
Python, Java		
Angular		

-		
Jenkins Maven		
GitLab, SAWCF, Docker		

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				

^ Back to Top

Affirmative ActionPhysically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.